globalmapper.com 2019-12-30

# Blue Marble Geographics Privacy Policy

It is very important to Blue Marble Geographics that you are able to maintain your privacy while you take advantage of all the Internet has to offer you. For this reason, Blue Marble Geographics will operate by the following principles. You agree to this Privacy Policy when you access or use the Blue Marble Geographics website ("the Site"). This Policy does not apply to the practices of companies we do not own or control, or to people that we do not employ or manage.

## Notice of Information Collected and Used

We will collect certain information when you visit or use the Site, including IP address, the type of browser and operating system that you use, your Internet Service Provider, cookie information, search queries you perform on the Site, and the page or other information that you requested ("Personal Information"). We will also collect Personal Information in connection with your usage of software offered through the Site.

Blue Marble Geographics uses Google Analytics on the Site and adheres to the [Google Analytics Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html). To learn more about how Google Analytics collects and processes data, read the Google article "[How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)." Blue Marble Geographics may use information that you provide to improve operations of the Site, for our customer service team to provide you with information that you request, and to customize your experience on the Site. We may also use the information collected for internal business purposes, to statistically analyze usage of the Site and the usage and performance of our software products, and to improve and customize the content and layouts of the Site and our products. We may use third parties to help us operate our business and the Site or to administer activities on our behalf. We also reserve the right to use this information in the aggregate to analyze usage of the Site. By visiting or supplying your Personal Information at the Site, you agree to allow us to provide such aggregate data to third parties.

Blue Marble Geographics does not sell or otherwise share any information you provide to us with any third parties.

## Information Sharing and Consent

Blue Marble Geographics will disclose Personal Information if required to do so by subpoena, court order, or legal process; or if we find that your actions on the Site or our products violate any usage guidelines for specific products or services.

## Use of Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that a website saves to your computer or mobile device to store information that you provide about yourself or to store your preferences. Blue Marble Geographics may use cookies to maintain information about your activity on the Site. Social media features (such as Facebook, for example) are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the Privacy Policy of the company providing it. Websites linked to or embedded within the Site may use their own cookies. This Privacy Policy does not address how these companies use their cookies. It is important for you to read the Privacy Policy and of each website you visit to ensure you are comfortable with how they may use your Personal Information.

## GDPR

Blue Marble Geographics takes your personal privacy very seriously. The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679 is a regulation in European Union law on data protection and privacy for all individuals within the European Union. It addresses the export of personal data outside the EU. This effort has come in to effect in May of 2018. In reviewing how to comply with this regulation for our European customers we decided to enact this as a policy for all of our customers worldwide. To that effect we will clarify that we are asking for your consent when obtaining personal information, we commit to a notification of a data breach event within 72 hours, and we will provide you with the "right to be forgotten" by Blue Marble. This web page is a first step in providing those tools. We will continue to expand our capabilities and flexibility in this process where reasonably possible over the course of the next year. There are certain scenarios with orders, invoicing and purchasing that will require further review so if you have any questions on how we will comply feel free to contact us.

Please contact us if you have any questions.

Last updated: May 24, 2017
